Guide to the Wayne A. Meeks Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Documentation of Professional Activities, Series II
  - "Response to James L. Kugel, Traditions of the Bible" - presented at the Society of Biblical Literature, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Pritchett Lecture, Ancient History & Mediterranean Archaeology Group, University of California, Berkeley, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "Apocalyptic Discourse and Strategies of Goodness" - presented at University of Chicago, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Henry Luce II Fellows in Theology Conference, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "How Can We Know Jesus?" - presented at Saint Michael's-on-the-Heights, Worcester, MA, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "The Mystery of St. Paul" - film proposed by Abraham Segal, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lecture at Harvard University Divinity School, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Anti-Judaism in the Fourth Gospel and Jewish-Christian Dialogue" conference in Leuven, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Association of Yale Alumni Trip: "The World of St. Paul: Judaism, Christianity and Greco-Roman Civilization", 2000 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "The Irony of Grace" for The Shaping of a Theological Mind: First Person Accounts of Theological Context and Methodology, edited by Darren C. Marks, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "Inventing the Christ: Multicultural Process and Poetry among the First Christians" - Alexander Robertson Lecture, University of Glasgow, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Association of Yale Alumni Trip, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Corinthian Christians as Artifical Aliens" for Paul: Beyond the Judaism/Hellenism Debate edited by Troels Engberg-Pedersen, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Five College Seminar on Biblical Literature, Amherst College, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS) 56th General Meeting, Montreal Canada, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Louisville Grawemeyer Award, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Regarding Orthodox Church liturgy, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Reviews and correspondence related to In Search of the Early Christians, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "Memoirs of a Convert to Social History" - presented at the Society of Biblical Literature meeting, Toronto, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Regarding "The Restless Curiosity of Nils Alstrup Dahl and His Probing of Ephesians", 2003 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Revisions for The First Urban Christians second edition, 2001-2003 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS) meeting in Durham Cathedral, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "Hope, Memory, and Transformation: How the Early Christians Learned to Imagine Jesus" -presentation at First Presbyterian Church, New Haven, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "A Nazi New Testament Professor Reads His Bible: The Strange Case of Gerhard Kittel", 2003 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Inventing the Christ: Multicultural Process and Poetry among the First Christians" - Dahl Lecture, Oslo and Yale Colloquy for New Testament Studies,; "The Restless Curiosity of Nils Alstrup Dahl", 2003 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Travel Itineraries, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS) 58th General Meeting, Bonn, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "Assisting the Word by Making (up) History" - Sprunt Lectures, "Biblical Faith and Faithful History," Union Theological Seminary, Richmond, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - "Assisting the Word by Making (up) History" in Interpretation: A Journal of Bible and Theology, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - "Christ Is the Question" - The McDonald Chair on The Life and Teachings of Jesus and Their Impact on Culture Lectures, Emory University, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Lectures include, "Does Anybody Know My Jesus? - Between Dogma and Romance," "Memory and Invention: The Making of Jesus Christ," " A Story To Think With: From Crucifixion to Metaphor," "The Bible Teaches ... through a Glass, Darkly," "Is Jesus the Last Word?"
  - "Christianity: A Religion Between Two Cultures," and Presidential address "Why Study the New Testament," Studiorum Novi Testamenti Societas (SNTS), Barcelona, 2004-08-04 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Interview for Christian Networks Journal, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Association of Yale Alumni Lectures, "Where do the gods come from?" and "Making the Christian Myth", 2004 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Society of Biblical Literature Annual Meeting in San Antonio, Texas, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Regarding Festschrift for Robert Morgan, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - "Christians in the City" - presented at Lutheran Church of the Redeemer, Atlanta, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - "On Being a Prophet in an Age of Madness, When Only Love Will Endure" - presented at University Presbyterian Church,Tuscaloosa, AL, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Association of Yale Alumni trip: "Islands of the Gods: An Exploration of the Classic Greek Islands", 2004 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - "Does Anybody Know My Jesus? Between Dogma and Romanticism" - presented at University of Texas, Austin, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - "Literalism, Common Sense, and the Price of Dogs" - presented at St. David's Church, Austin Texas, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "Inventing the Christ: Multicultural Process and Poetry Among the First Christians" - Crognan Bicentennial Lecture Series, Williams College, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Regarding Christ is the Question (John Knox Press), 2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Society of Biblical Literature, Annual Meeting in Philadelphia, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Foreword for Paul and the Anatomy of Apostolic Authority, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Social and Ecclesial Life of Christians," in Cambridge History of Christianity I; Early Christianity: Origins to Constantine, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Response to Wayne A. Meeks' Christ is the Question by Luke Timothy Johnson, Society of Biblical Literature, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "Living by the Bible: Literalism, Common Sense, and the Price of Dogs," in The Yale Review, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Westminster John Knox Press, Lectionary Commentary Series, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "The History of Religions School" in The New Cambridge History of the Bible, Volume IV: Modernity, Colonialism, and their successors, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "To Tell The Truth," "Living by the Bible: the Bad, the Good, and the Question" - Carmichael- Walling Lectures on New Testament & Early Christianity, Abilene Christian University, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "What Did Corinth Teach Paul?" - presented at "Saint Paul the Apostle and Corinth" conference, Greece, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - "Swallowing Jonah: Christianity's Borrowed Identity and the Prophet Who Wouldn't" - presented at Emory University, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - "What is the Bible Anyway?" - presented at Trinity Presbyterian Church, Atlanta, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "Swallowing Jonah: Scripture and Identity in Early Christianity," in Living Texts: Religious Experience, the New Testament and the Theological Appropriation of Scripture, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - "Does the Bible Clearly Teach...Anything?" Lenten Study Retreat, White Memorial Presbyterian Church, Raleigh, NC, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Contemporary Civilization Faculty Meeting on New Testament at Columbia University, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - "Paul and the Roman Provinces" - presented at Congres Internacional Pau, Frucuos I El Cristianisme Primitui a Tarragona", 2008 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Association of Yale Alumni trip: North Africa's Mediterranean Coast Through the Centuries, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - "The Rise and Fall of Historicism (and What Do We Do Now?)", 2010 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - From "Gospel" to Life of Jesus: "According to Mark", 2010 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - "Naming Jesus: History, Midrash, and Myth", 2010 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - "The Myth of the Self-Interpreting Text Communities Making Scripture Making Communities" - presented at Smith College, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - "From Jerusalem to Illyricum, Rome to Spain: The World of Paul's Missionary Imagination" in The Rise and Expansion of Christianity in the First Three Centuries, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Association of Yale Alumni trip: "From the Strait of Gibraltar to the Canals of Venice: A Voyage Exploring the Crossroads of Cultures in the Mediterranean Sea" - Lecture: "Mapping the Mediterranean World: Caesar Augustus and St. Paul,", 2011 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - "From Jerusalem to Illyricum, Rome to Spain: The World of Paul's Missionary Imagination" - presented in Athens, Thessalonika, 2011 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - "The Problem of Christian Living: Is Authentic Community Possible?" in Beyond Bultmann, 2014 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - "Kingdom of David" - PBS Series (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Judaism, Hellenism, and the Birth of Christianity" - unidentified text (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Sailing to Byzantium: "Visions on Patmos: John's Apocalypse," and "The Christ of Byzantium: Images of Jesus in Bible, Liturgy, and Art" (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Transparencies for presentation on the Apocalypse (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "The Social World of Pauline Christianity", Draft (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Yale Symposium on Apocalypticism in Early Christianity (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "Constantine and the Imperial Church" (Box 14, Folder 7)
- HarperCollins Study Bible Project, Series III
  New Revised Standard Version of the Bible Study Edition of which Meeks was General Editor
  - Administrative files
    - Editorial Board (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Expenses, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Guidelines, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - List of Contributors, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Plans, 1989-1993 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Publicity (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Prospectus, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence with Contributors, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence with Contributors, 1989-1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Contributors, 1989-1993 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Contributors, 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Contributors, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with James Mays, 1985-1987 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Harper Collins, 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Harper Collins, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Invitations, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Courses Taught, Series IV
  - Seminar in Christian Origins, Indiana University, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Johannine Christianity, Yale University (1 of 2), 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Johannine Christianity, Yale University (2 of 2), 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Social Description of Early Christianity, Yale University (1 of 3), 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Social Description of Early Christianity, Yale University (2 of 3), 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Social Description of Early Christianity, Yale University (3 of 3), 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Jews and Christians in Greco Roman Cities, Yale University, 1978-1979 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Christian-Jewish Debate in the First Four Centuries, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Christian-Jewish Debate in the First Four Centuries, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
  - Religious Studies Seminar (1 of 2), Yale University, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Religious Studies Seminar, Yale University (2 of 2), 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Rise of Christianity to Power, Yale University, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Apocalypticism in Early Christianity, Yale University, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Ethos and Ethics in Josephus, Yale University, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - NT Ancient Christianity Seminar, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Readings in the Greek New Testament, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Problems in Christian Ethics, Yale University (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Problems in Christian Ethics, Yale University (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Studies in the 4th Gospel, Yale University (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Studies in the 4th Gospel, Yale University (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Religious Communities in Rome, Yale University (1 of 2), 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Religious Communities in Rome, Yale University (2 of 2), 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Inventing Jesus Christ, Williams College, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Course Syllabi, 1990-1999 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Dissertations Advised, Series V
  - Alexander, 1993-1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Aus, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Bechard, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Berry, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Blanton, 2000-2004 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Boguslawski, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Borowski, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Clark-Soles, 1996-2000 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Collins, 1972-1977 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Crislip, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - D'Angelo, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Davis, 1995-1996 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Donahue, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Eriksson, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Garrett, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Greer, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Hawkins, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Henrich, 1992-1993 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - A. Hilton, 1993-1996 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Hoffman, 1993-1996 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Hultin, 2001-2003 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Hunt, 1993-1996 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Hutson, 1992-1997 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Johnson, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Just, 1994-1997 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Krawiec, 1993-1995 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Kuck, 1984-1987 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Lazding-Zusevics, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Lewis, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Martin, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Mitchell, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Nave, 1997-2000 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Parsenios, 2000-2001 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Peterson, 1994-1997 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Plunkett-Dowling, 1997-2001 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Royalty, 1993-1995 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Schein, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Shiner, 1986-1988 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Simas, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Snyder, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Wansink, 1990-1993 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Van Doren (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Ware, 1992-1994 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Weidman, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - White, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Yarbrough, 1980-1983 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Yieh, 1989-2003 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous dissertation proposals, 1990-1998 (Box 20, Folder 17)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series VI
  - Biographical documentation: Curriculum Vitae (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Regarding campus ministry activities, 1959-1966 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Notices and correspondence regarding academic appointments, 1966-1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Tributes and awards, 1975-1981, no date (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Photographic portraits of Meeks, no date (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Audio-visual material: photographs, digital copies of slides (5 CDs) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Images from Prof. Meeks' slide collection were entered in the Yale Divinity Library's EIKON: Image Database for Biblical Studies